Atlantic Union Committee Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part III: Subject File, 1947-1968 (Box 95-122)
  - Students convention, 1952-1957
  - Tennessee, 1950-1952
  - Topeka State Journal, 1949
  - Trends of communist propaganda, 1954
  - United Nations, 1950-1954, (2 folders)
  - United World Federalists, 1949-1951
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars
    - General, 1951
    - Magazine, 1955
  - Victory dinner, Washington, D.C., 1960-1961 (Box 122)
  - Voice of America, 1952
  - Waldorf Astoria dinner, New York, N.Y., 1951
  - Washington, D.C., branch, 1951-1953
  - Washington Journalism Center, 1967
  - White House Task Force on the Education of Gifted Persons, 1968
  - Wilton Park, England
    - General, 1964-1967
    - Institute of International Relations, 1967
  - Women for Union of the Free, 1949-1950
  - World government materials, 1949-1950
  - World Population Control Council, 1967
- Part III: Speeches and Statements, 1948-1967 (Box 123-124)
  Handwritten and typewritten drafts, notes, and correspondence relating to speeches, statements, and miscellaneous writings.
  Arranged by type of material and therein chronologically by year.
  - Correspondence, 1950-1955 (Box 123)
  - General, 1948-1967, undated, (7 folders); (3 folders) (Box 124)
  - Radio scripts, undated
- Part III: Miscellany, 1949-1967 (Box 124-130)
  Financial records, photographs, press releases, printed matter, newspaper clippings, and other miscellany.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Financial records (Box 124)
    - Audit report and financial statement, 1954-1957
    - Budget, 1955-1957
    - Financial statements, 1952-53
    - Income taxes, 1949-1959
    - Insurance, 1949-1963
    - New York branch, chapter finance report, 1952-1954
    - New York State unemployment tax, 1949-1955 (Box 125)
    - Payroll records, 1949-1953, (2 folders)
    - Philadelphia, Pa., chapter finance report, 1956
    - Statements of revenues and expenditures, 1953
  - Miscellaneous items, 1950-1961 (Box 126)
  - Press releases, 1949-1967, (7 folders)
  - Printed matter, 1949-1959, (2 folders) (Box 127)
  - Clippings
    - 1949, (2 folders)
    - 1949-1950, (4 folders) (Box 128)
    - 1950-1951, (5 folders) (Box 129)
    - 1952-1953, (3 folders) (Box 130)
  - Photographs
- Part IV: Subject File, 1946-1960 (Box 131-136)
  Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, circulars, pamphlets, photographs, congressional resolutions, notes, press releases and statements, newspaper clippings, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material.
  - General correspondence, 1951-1960 (Box 131)
  - Atlantic Union, convention
    - Agenda, 1957
    - Delegates, 1957
    - European support, 1949-1955
  - Board of governors and Executive Committee, minutes, 1956-1958
  - Brookings Institution, Washington, D.C., study, 1953
  - Bylaws and constitution, 1949-1956
  - Campaign handbook, undated
  - Catechism, 1954
  - Chapters
    - General, 1949-1953
    - Memphis, Tenn., 1946-1950
  - Circulars, 1949-1952 (Box 132)
  - Citizens' Conference delegates, 1954
  - Commission to Study Atlantic Relations, 1951-1952
  - Committee for Board of Governors, 1957
  - Committee for Liaison with National Organizations, 1951
  - Committees, general, 1949-1956
  - Conferences
    - General, 1950-1953, (2 folders)
    - Ottawa, Canada, 1952
    - Projected, 1957
    - Washington, D.C., 1951-1952, (2 folders)
  - Congress
    - 1951
    - 1952-1958, (4 folders) (Box 133)
  - Contributions, 1949-1950
  - Council
    - General, 1949-1959
    - Invitations, 1949-1952
  - Executive Committee, 1958-1959
  - Executive director, prospects, 1953
  - Field organization, 1951-1952
  - Finance
    - Committee, 1950-1952
    - Lists, 1949-1950, undated
  - Financial, 1949-1959, (2 folders) (Box 134)
  - Fund-raising, 1949-1951
  - Incorporation, 1949
  - Membership Committee, 1949-1952
  - Memoranda, 1955-1959
  - New England Atlantic Union Council, 1952
  - News, 1949-1956, (2 folders)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, strengthening of, 1953
  - Origins, 1948-1949
  - Osborn, Stellanova Brunt (Mrs. Chase), German contacts, 1955-1956
  - Photographs, undated
  - Political Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 135)
  - Press
    - Clippings, 1949-1955
    - Releases and statements, 1949-1958
  - Promotion, 1949-1956, undated
  - Public Relations Committee, 1949-1952
  - Publicity, 1949-1953
  - Trips, Paris, France, 1953
  - United States
    - Congress
      - Anti-Atlantic union, 1950-1952
      - General, 1949-1956
    - Neutral Atlantic union, 1949-1951
    - Pro-Atlantic union, 1949-1955
    - Senate, hearings, 1950, (2 folders) (Box 136)
  - United World Federalists, cooperation, 1949-1952
  - Miscellany, 1949-1956, undated